[Music]
an online survey of personal mosquito
repellent strategies Unearthed all sorts
of strange strategems from cutting a
tomato in half and leaving it next to
the bed to rubbing yourself with
cigarette butts soaked in alcohol you
could also soak yourself in alcohol with
a gin and tonic cut down on sugar cut
out meat or
bananas but what's funny is some say
avoid bananas some say eat bananas to
Stave off mosquitoes and others say
topically rub them on your skin I don't
even want to know about what else you
might do with them eat bananas avoid
bananas you don't know until you put it
to the test the impact of the
consumption of bananas on attraction of
a malaria mosquito to humans researchers
in Wis and randomized subjects to eat
grapes or bananas before testing what
they then tasted like to mosquitoes and
the ingestion of bananas was strongly
associated with an increase in the
number of mosquito contacts for hours
after eating a banana translating to
about 11 extra contacts after 1 hour and
seven contacts after 2 hours meanwhile
the ingestion of grapes had no effect
interestingly it didn't seem to matter
how many bananas you eat at once as
eating Three Bananas didn't appear to
make people people any tastier than
eating one bottom line after years of
repeat experiments They concluded that
ingestion of bananas but not grapes
resulted in a significantly higher
attraction of mosquitoes for hours after
ingestion on average though some people
did appear to be immune to the banana
effect what about that Jin and tonic
some have suggested alcohol will keep
the bugs away others suggest we might
suffer more mosquito bites after
ingesting liquor uh well there's only
one one way to find out drink some beer
and put your arm in a box with some
mosquitoes the title of the study gives
it away alcohol ingestion stimulates
mosquito attraction about 40% of the
mosquitoes landed on their arms before
drinking a bottle of beer compared to
about 50% afterwards and it didn't
appear to have anything to do with
changes in sweat production or skin
temperature after the booze it might
just be something you start exuding
after you drink and so it's also not
just because you got you know bit a
bunch of times CU you're like blacked
out in an alley or something the
researchers concluded that since the
percent of mosquitoes landing on
volunteers significantly increased after
beer ingestion drinking alcohol
stimulates mosquito attraction but it
could just be drinking beer not
necessarily all alcohol and they only
tested one species of mosquito the one
that transmits diseases like Deni zika
and yellow fever what about gauging
human attractiveness to malaria
mosquitoes before now after volunteers
consumed either beer using 25 Volunteers
in a total of 2500 mosquitoes or water
as a control with 18 volunteers and only
about 1,800 mosquitoes and water
consumption had no effect but beer
consumption increased the attractiveness
of the volunteers it's like the
mosquitoes put on beer goggles beer
consumption increases human
attractiveness to date bananas and beer
are the only dietary components that
have been shown to increase mosquito
attraction okay but we want to repel
mosquitoes not attract them what about
testing B vitamins as a home remedy
against mosquitoes B vitamins are often
recommended in the popular media as a
systemic repellent against mosquitoes
especially on the web the first studies
day back over a half century they gave
people doses of vitamins B1 and B6 yet
in a series of subsequent tests the
mosquitoes probed avidly and BP promptly
the only tested the vitamins on four
people but the vitamins appeared so
useless they didn't think it worth
repeating the experiments in view of the
obvious lack of repellency of these
vitamins we believe the researchers
wrote that we have disproved the Notions
that vitamins taken orally acce mosquito
repellent but they only tested vitamins
B1 and B6 what about B2 B3 B5 B9 B12 you
don't know until you put it to the test
these are the results of a small number
number of published studies like the one
I showed that suggest that vitamin B
complex supplements are not effective as
repellent but these studies were limited
by the use of very few human subjects
only one species of mosquito and a
limited number of B vitamins so
researchers decided to put it to rest
once and for all B1 B2 B3 B5 B6 B7 also
known as biotin B9 B12 they also just
tried a megad do of thamin B1 which is
rumored to be the most effective B and
nothing no effect of vitamin B
supplementation any of them I mean it'd
be nice to have an effective oral insect
repellent unfortunately vitamin B1 has
been proved to be ineffective and this
includes so-called mosquito repellent
patches that supposedly deliver B1
through the skin no protection provided
whatsoever bottom line vitamin B1 also
known as thy and is not a systemic
mosquito repellent in men they also
tried smearing it on people's skin with
failure after failure you start feeling
bad for the volunteers seated in a room
with their shirts off then they just
release a 100 suckers into the room oh
look at some of those bite rates these
are btes per minute up to 96 bites per
minute just think how bad it would have
been if they had had some bananas and
[Music]
beer for